# Andrea Risjord

# **UX/UI** Designer and Researcher

Minneapolis, MN

I am a User Experience Researcher and Designer who enjoys understanding human stores through thorough and empathetic research. It's important to me to learn about people's stories to cultivate connection and empathy in our world. Discovering ways to problem solve and find resolution scratches my itch for efficiency and order.

I specialize in problem-finding and solving using intuitive and clean design. My design aesthetic is influenced by my studies in art history and anthropology, as well as my life experiences.

## **Experience**

Custom Picture Frame Designer, Nash Frame Design 8/2021 - present

- Creating custom designs for a diverse range of artwork by working in collaboration with the client and production studio to create unique, beautiful, and functional designs.
- On-the-spot problem solving, managing client and vendor relations, frequent and detailed communication between various departments throughout a project.
- Managing several projects at once while also dealing with real-time customers and sales.

Department Lead Production Artist, Mercury Mosaics 5/2017 - 5/2021

- Managing orders as they move through production in coordination with the schedule and production manager.
- Coordinating with other departments to quickly produce a high-quality product in a high-pressure environment.
- Training new employees and writing instruction manuals.

# **Design Skills**

User Surveys
User Interviews
Scenario Design
User Persona Creation
Usability Testing
Copywriting
User Flow
Prototyping
UI Design
Creativity
Code Conversational

## **Soft Skills**

Problem-Solving Adaptability Collaboration Empathy Project Management Leadership

### **Tools**

Figma Figjam Miro Github HTML/CSS

### Education

University of Minnesota 2023 UX/UI Design Bootcamp Program

Emory University 2010 -2014 BA in Art History and Visual Arts Minor in Anthropology

### **Lets Connect**

andrearisjord.com

andreaisjord@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrearisjord